<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Roelfs</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daniel Roelfs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Bach</title>
      <link>/blog/analyzing-bach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/analyzing-bach/</guid>
      <description>@import url(&#39;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=IM+Fell+English|IM+Fell+English+SC&amp;display=swap&#39;); body{ background-color: #FFFFF0; } h1 { font-family: &#39;IM Fell English&#39;, serif; } h2,h3,h4,h5,h6 { font-family: &#39;IM Fell English&#39;, serif; } .post-title { font-family: &#39;IM Fell English SC&#39;, serif; font-size: 6rem; }  Introduction A little while ago I was watching a documentary series on Dutch television about one of the most beloved composers in the Netherlands: Johann Sebastian Bach. I had
 Collecting the data In my search of a dataset, I found this old website, looking like it last got a major update in 2003, made by what appeared to be a Bach enthousiast called Bryen Travis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Create Manhattan Plots Using ggplot</title>
      <link>/blog/how-i-create-manhattan-plots-using-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-i-create-manhattan-plots-using-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There are many ways to create a Manhattan plot. There’s a number of online tools that create Manhattan plots for you, it’s implemented in a number of toolboxes that are often used in genetics, and there’s a couple of packages for R that can create these plots. However, these options often don’t offer the customizability that some people (like me) would want. One of the most flexible ways to plot a Manhattan plot (I know of) is the {manhattan} package, but how nice would it be to have full control over the properties of the plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Plot ERPs in R</title>
      <link>/blog/how-i-plot-erps-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-i-plot-erps-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Plotting ERPs is one of the essential skills in EEG neuroscience. There are many possible ways of going about this task, some better than others. Myself, I use either MATLAB or R to plot ERPs. In my experience, MATLAB is by far the preferred method since most of the EEG analysis takes place in MATLAB already, but I believe that there’s some merit to using R. One of my main arguments is aesthetics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cv_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv_page/</guid>
      <description>Curriculum Vitæ --   Daniel Roelfs
PhD Candidate  Download PDF-- daniel.roelfs[a]medisin.uio.no danielroelfs.com  Profile  Biomedical researcher with a particular interest in the intersection between neuroimaging and genetics in the domain of neurobiology and psychiatry.  Skills  Neuroimaging Study planning, collection, and analysis of various types of neuroimaging types, most notably fMRI, diffusion imaging and EEG.
 Genetics Performing genome-wide association studies and calculating polygenic risk scores and genetic correlations across phenotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m Daniel Roelfs, I’m a PhD candidate working at the Norwegian Centre for Mental Disorders Research (NORMENT) in Oslo. My research focuses on the intersection between neuroimaging and genetics to discover more about the human brain and schizophrenia in particular. I’m enrolled in a doctoral education programme at the University of Oslo.
Originally from the Netherlands, I have also studied in France and Sweden before moving to Norway. In my free time I ski, photograph, and make music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitæ</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>h1 { color:#ffffff; font-family:&#39;Libre Baskerville&#39;, serif; letter-spacing:0em; margin:0 0 0 0; font-size:0rem; line-height:0rem }  /* Copyright (c) 2009, Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. Code licensed under the BSD License: http://developer.yahoo.net/yui/license.txt version: 2.7.0 */ html { color: #000; background: #FFF; } body, div, dl, dt, dd, ul, ol, li, h1, h2, h3, h4, h5, h6, pre, code, form, fieldset, legend, input, button, textarea, p, blockquote, th, td { margin: 0; padding: 0; } table { border-collapse: collapse; border-spacing: 0; } fieldset, img { border: 0; } address, caption, cite, code, dfn, em, strong, th, var, optgroup { font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit; } del, ins { text-decoration: none; } li { list-style: none; } caption, th { text-align: left; } h1, h2, h3, h4, h5, h6 { font-size: 100%; font-weight: normal; } q:before, q:after { content: &#39;&#39;; } abbr, acronym { border: 0; font-variant: normal; } sup { vertical-align: baseline; } sub { vertical-align: baseline; } legend { color: #000; } input, button, textarea, select, optgroup, option { font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit; } input, button, textarea, select { *font-size: 100%; } body { font: 13px/1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>First publication is on its way, I promise! :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>