<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on Daniel Roelfs</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on Daniel Roelfs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Everything is a Linear Model</title>
      <link>/blog/everything-is-a-linear-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/everything-is-a-linear-model/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine you&amp;rsquo;re incredibly lazy and you want to learn R, but you only want to learn one function to do statistics. What function do you learn? I&amp;rsquo;d recommend to learn to use the lm() function. Why? Because most common statistical tests are in fact nothing more than some variation of a linear model, from the simplest One-Sample T-test to a repeated-measures ANOVA. I think most people that have Googled for this question have found Jonas Lindeløv&amp;rsquo;s post on how common statistical tests are linear models (as they should, it&amp;rsquo;s an amazing post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Basic Comparison Between Factor Analysis, PCA, and ICA</title>
      <link>/blog/a-basic-comparison-between-factor-analysis-pca-and-ica/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/a-basic-comparison-between-factor-analysis-pca-and-ica/</guid>
      <description>This is just a very quick blog post outlining some of the commonalities and differences between factor analysis (FA), principal component analysis (PCA), and independent component analysis (ICA). I was inspired to write some of this down through some confusion caused in the lab by SPSS&#39; apparent dual usage of the term &amp;ldquo;factor analysis&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;principal components&amp;rdquo;. A few of my colleagues who use SPSS showed me the following screen:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running an ICA on Questionnaires</title>
      <link>/blog/running-an-ica-on-questionnaires/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/running-an-ica-on-questionnaires/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If there was a statistics magazine and it were to have ads, the ad for independent component analysis (commonly referred to as the ICA) might read something like this:
 Do you ever find yourself with a large number of highly related variables? Are you interested in studying constructs rather than specific measures? Would you rather work with a small number of variables each capturing a large amount of variance instead of a large number of variables each capturing a small amount of variance?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
